[Music]
so with 2024 release Wave 2 co-pilot in
business Central can help you generate
new modify existing or alleviate you of
the pain of preparing number series for
the next year I'm Ian ktic I'm a product
manager in business Central team join me
for the next couple of minutes to show
you how the new co-pilot capabilities
help you with number
Series so getting started fast uh on new
implementation or recurring maintenance
or simply rolling out a new module or a
new
company uh usually requires uh a bit of
time and money uh co-pilot can reduce
the time it takes to set up number
series and make their maintenance quick
and easy for example when you need to
update a year or month based numbering
to many d or posted documents in
business Central so without me talking
more about it let's see the co-pilot in
action I'm in business Central and my
company decided to uh uh roll out a
service management module looking at a
service management
setup I can see that there are some
number series uh that are missing so let
me open number series
and let's see how uh co-pilot can
actually help me what I can do is I can
click the generate button in here to
open the the prom dialogue and in here I
can actually instruct the co-pilot to
generate the number series for I think I
saw uh contract credit members missing a
uh number series if you looking for
inspiration there are a couple of prompt
guides that can help you get inspired
with the with the prompts of of uh
creating new number series modifying
existing or preparing uh one for the
next year what I'll do in here is I will
paste uh one of the prompts that I have
where I want uh contract credit memo
number series to be created you can just
end it in there and the co-pilot can uh
do its magic or you can supplement it
with additional things for example in
here I explicitly ask a co-pilot to
create a number series that will include
the last two digit of the number so it
needs to have 24 somewhere in the uh in
the number series and the numbers that
it's going to generate because I know
the accountant for example really do
love seeing that on on the posted
documents for example where that it
gives them an indication of when that
which uh which fiscal year that posted
document uh belongs to so let's see what
a co-pilot comes up
with okay so it has created a suggestion
for the the contract credit memo as I
asked it and what you can see in here is
actually the the the numbering of the
contract credit memos will include 24
the year that I asked it to do and when
I actually go ahead and click keep it
it's going to insert the number Series
so let's see contract so you can see
contract credit memo and what is even
cooler it's actually going to uh update
the numbers serious also on the service
management setup this is just this is
just so cool and so mind-blowing right
so the next thing I want to try it out I
want to try out is since okay this is an
initial number series that uh got
created for the contract credit memos
but let's see how how co-pilot actually
handles uh preparing for the uh for the
next year so let me go back to number
series and let me generate again and in
here as you can see the prompt guy
actually has these uh sort of templates
for for the prompts where you can say
set up number series for the next year
meaning you know go through all of the
number series and set them up for the
next year which is great but we'll limit
ourselves only for that one that uh we
have just created and we'll say let's
prepare it for the next
year all right what you can see right
now it it actually found a couple of uh
credit memo number series which is the
reason why we always say in here AI
generated content might be incorrect we
didn't ask for the sales credit memo but
we did ask for the contract credit memo
and I will delete this one because this
one I don't need and this one I also
don't need because I know that my uh
number serious for the contract credit
memo was uh service management contract
credit memo and what's cool about this
is you can see that it it has actually
respected the rule that we've uh
introduced with the first number series
for the current year right let's see
what happens when I say keep it right
and let's have a look at this contract
credit members what you can see it
actually it created an additional number
series line and it actually set the
starting date uh for the 1 of January
2025 I mean if this isn't mindblowing I
don't know what is it I'm so happy to
see this this uh this thing in action
and one last thing that I want to show
you which I'm sure is going to blow your
mind is another thing where you are
where we will start from a completely
empty company and ask the co-pilot to
generate the number series for the
company let's switch to an empty
company and let's go to number
series and what you can see in here I
have just the two number series nothing
else is in there I mean we can even
delete those
right and I'll hit generate and as you
saw in here in the create new promp
guide there's this create number series
for the new company I can use that
template or I can use a slightly
adjusted one that I've created to make
things a bit more difficult for the
co-pilot and for you to see the full
power of it right so we'll ask you to
create the number series for everything
in business Central for the new company
but what want to do is my accounting
department actually said for all the
poster documents make sure that there is
a year number included in that so let's
hit generate and see what it comes up
with so generating number series for all
of the modules general ledger sales
purchase inventory it'll switch to Pro
jobs uh to to projects to
resources to manufacturing service
management it will go through all of the
modules and the reason why it will go
through all of the modules is because
this particular company has this user
experience set to premium which means
you know you need to set up all the
number series and here it is look at all
of the number series that the co-pilot
created let's take a closer look at some
of those posted documents that I've
explicitly asked to include the year
number you can see the posted assembly
order has 24 in there let's scroll a bit
down posted receipts have the year
number in it I mean this is just uh
great let's keep the suggestion in here
and as you can see all of the number
series have been added in here and
what's even cooler about it yeah let's
just go to purchase
setup and I mean look at all of this
this has just been said by the co-pilot
and you're ready to go of course from
the perspective of uh number series all
right so what you saw in this grade demo
is that you can use co-pilot to help you
with number series it can generate them
or modify existing ones for a specific
record for a specific module or for an
entire company and what's more about it
it can actually help you maintain those
number series easily with a simple
prompt and using the prompt guides
prompt guides that uh show up in the
prom dialogue it'll make your it will
make a lot of consultants and a lot of
admins lives a way way much easier by
removing that chore that they needed to
do on a periodic
basis I hope you enjoyed this uh video
as much as I did make sure to try out
these uh new improvements that kilot
brings to uh number series and also make
sure to check out the description that
is below uh the video uh for more
content and useful links thank you for
your time